接下来我们要动态生成内容
next up we want to dynamically generate content
通过渲染一些模板文件
by rendering some template files
我们的模板将混合 html 和电子代码
our templates will be a mix of html and electric code
类似于您可能使用过的模板
similar to templates you may have used with
其他网络框架
other web frameworks
我们将使用理解
and we'll use a comprehension
保持模板代码简洁明了
to keep the template code nice and succinct
现在我们在控制器中生成 html
right now we're generating html inside the controller
但是让我们改变一下
but let's change it up
为我们制作一个模板
to make a template that does this for us
是的，我们将为模板创建一个新目录
yeah we'll make a new directory for templates
我们有这个页面目录
we've got this pages directory
但那是我们的静态文件
but that's for our static file
所以让我们在调查下创建一个新目录
so let's create a new directory under survey
我们称之为模板
and we'll call it templates
然后我们开始
and then we'll start
使用我们的索引操作的模板
with the template for our index action
所以我要调用那个索引
so I'm going to call that index
按照惯例，它会有扩展名
and by convention that's going to have the extension
ex 代表嵌入式长生不老药
ex which stands for embedded elixir
我已经有了我们模板奶嘴的大纲
and I already have an outline for our template teat up
所以我们想要一个有盟友的 ul
so we want a ul with allies
我们希望在此处插入名称
and we want the name to get interpolated right here
然后我们还将插入熊的类型
and then we'll also interpolate the type of bear
以同样的方式让我们有一个展示模板
in the same way let's have a show template
显示前，我也有它的轮廓
show ex and I've got an outline of it as well
我们只会用一个 h one 说 show bear
we're just going to use an h one saying show bear
是熊，不管他们叫什么名字
is the bear whatever their name is
休眠，我们将显示 true 或 false
hibernating and we're going to display true or false
所以我们需要阅读这些模板文件
so we need to read these template files
然后动态填写值
and then dynamically fill in the values
事实证明，elixir 有一个模块
and it turns out elixir has a module
这可以快速解决这个问题
that makes quick work of this
ex 模块并不奇怪
no surprises the ex module
现在我们对邪恶文件功能感兴趣
now we're interested in the evil file function
第一个参数是模板文件的名称
the first argument is the name of the template file
在这种情况下，他们有样本
in this case they have sample
性别和第二个参数是关键字列表
sex and the second argument is a keyword list of
绑定名称和值
bindings names and values
可以在模板内部引用
that can be referenced inside of the template
所以如果我们有样品前
so if we have sample ex
那么食物只是那里的一些静态文本
then food is just some static text in there
然后我们使用小于 % 等于
and then we use less than % equals
在 bar 和 % 大于这样
in bar and % greater than like that
好吧，这整件事都会被取代
well this whole thing is going to get replaced
按 bar 的值
by the value of bar
这是低音
which is bass
所以这个输出是food bass
so the output of this is food bass
现在，如果您是 Rails 程序员
now if you're a rails programmer
这种语法实际上看起来很熟悉
this syntax will actually look quite familiar
是的，它类似于 ruby 的 erb
yeah it's similar to ruby's erb
所以开始吧
so to start things off
在裸控制器中
in the bare controller
我们需要获取模板文件的绝对路径
we need to get the absolute path to the template file
我们实际上
and we actually
已经知道该怎么做
already know how to do that
我们完成了它和处理程序
we did it over and handler
是的，它在顶部
yeah it's up here at the top
我们有我们的页面路径，所以我要复制它
we have our pages path so I'm just going to copy it
转到这里的裸控制器
go over to bare controller up here
将其粘贴并将其更改为模板路径
paste it in and change this to templates path
和模板
and templates
现在我们需要稍微改变一下这条管道
now we need to change this pipeline down here a little
我们想看看所有的熊
bit we want to see all the bears
所以我要删除过滤器是灰熊
so I'm going to remove the filter for is grizzly
我们也不需要改造这些打击
we also don't need to transform these struck
不再是熊的物品
into bear items anymore
因为
because
ul 和 alli 将在
the ul and the alli is going to get generated in the
模板，所以我可以删除它
template so I can remove that
当我在它的时候，我会删除这个
and while I'm at it I'll remove this
函数，因为我们不需要它
function because we're not going to need it
也不再
anymore either
然后我们也可以删除这个连接
and then we can also remove this join
因为我们不需要加入列表
because we don't need to join the list
变成一个字符串了
into a string anymore
这将返回一个熊的列表
this is going to return a list of bears
我们只是要对那些进行排序
we're just going to sort those
所以现在我们又回到了熊市名单
so now we're back to having a list of bear struck
然后是我们想要的响应体
and then for the response body what we want
是评估模板的内容
is the content of that evaluated template
所以这只是满足
so this is just going to be content
我们将在此处创建该内容
we're going to create that content right here
内容相等
content equal
我们将采用我们的模板路径
we're going to take our templates path
我们将把它通过管道连接到路径连接中
we're going to pipe it into path join
指数前
index ex
这将为我们提供一条绝对路径
that's going to give us an absolute path to that
模板文件
template file
然后我们将把它输入
then we're going to pipe that into
ex evil 文件就是我们刚刚看到的函数
ex evil file that's the function we just looked at
它以文件名作为第一个参数
it takes a file name as the first argument
将从左侧通过管道输入
which is going to be piped in from the left
然后我们可以给它我们的绑定
and then we can give it our bindings
所以我们想要这个名字
so we want the name
熊在我们的模板中参考
bears in our template to refer
达到我们空头名单中的价值
to the value that's in our bears list
这东西就在这里
this thing set right up here
现在因为这个关键字列表是
now because this keyword list is the
函数的最后一个参数
last argument to the function
我们实际上可以去掉方括号
we can actually drop the square brackets
所以在索引模板中
so in the index template
让我们从检查熊名单开始
let's start by inspecting the list of bears
是的，我会把它放在我们的静态文本下面
yeah I'll just put it below our static text right here
我们使用少于 %
we use less than %
等于
equals
这就是我们将值插入模板的方式
that's how we interpolate values into a template
然后 % 比那样大
and then % greater than like that
我将使用检查功能
I'm going to use the inspect function
就这样我们看到了原始的
just so we see the raw
熊的形式
form of bears
把它存起来
save that away
如果我们查看响应
if we look at the response
我们看到我们有一个熊市名单
what we see we have a list of bear struck
所以我们需要做的只是循环
so all we need to do is just loop
在这个熊的名单上
over this list of bears
并生成一个 html 行项目或盟友
and generate an html line item or an ally
对于列表中的每个元素
for each element in the list
所以让我们继续填写这个模板
so let's go ahead and fill out this template
在我们想要生成盟友的 ul 内部
inside of the ul we want to generate allies
所以我要从这里开始
so I'm going to start just here
我们将使用小于等于
we'll use less than % equal
假设我们有一个熊变量及其名称
let's say we have a bear variable and its name
我们将在那里插入
we'll interpolate that right there
以同样的方式我们将拥有
in the same way we'll have
像这样的熊型
bear type like that
好的，但我们需要生成其中之一
okay but we need to generate one of these
对于熊列表中的每个元素
for every element that's in the bears list
一种方法是使用 em map
and one way to do that would be to use em map
现在
now
不要跟随，因为这将无法生存
don't follow along because this isn't going to survive
很长一段时间
for very long
但我们可以这样做
but we could do this
我点图
me dot map
承担每一个
bears for every one of those
我们生成一个列表项
we generate a list item
然后我们需要确保关闭它
and then we need to make sure to close this off
低于 % 和
down here less than % and
上帝记得在那里做括号
god remember to do that parentheses right there
像那样把它存起来
like that save that away
重新加载
reload
看起来它有效
and it looks like it worked
我们所有的熊都在 ul
we have all of our bears in a ul
它们整齐地隐藏在列表项中
and they're neatly tucked away inside of a list item
好的，所以使用鸸鹋地图肯定有效
okay so using emu map certainly works
但语法是理想的
but the syntax is an ideal
尤其是这个匿名函数
especially with this anonymous function
实际上真的很难输入
it was actually really difficult to type in
是的，这里的简单循环结构肯定会很好
yeah simple looping construct here sure would be nice
嘿，这给了我们一个使用理解的机会
and hey this gives us a chance to use a comprehension
你可能以前没有看过理解
you may not have seen a comprehension before
所以让我们从这个简单的例子开始
so let's start with this simple example
记得我们在列表中使用 map 1 2 3
remember when we used map on a list 1 2 3
并给它一个匿名函数
and gave it an anonymous function
这使所有数字增加了两倍
and that tripled all the numbers
好吧，这是做同样的方法
well here's the way to do the same
有理解的东西
thing with a comprehension
我们使用四个
we use four
xa 左箭头
x a left pointing arrow
然后我们给它一个列表 1 2 3 在这种情况下
then we give it a list 1 2 3 in this case
一个逗号然后做，我们可以给它一个块
a comma and then do and we can give it a block
这是单行理解，所以我将使用
this is a single line comprehension so I'll use
逗号做冒号
comma do colon
然后我们将数字 x 乘以三倍
and then we triple the numbers x times three
就这样
just like that
所以这很酷
so that's pretty cool this
x 向左箭头，然后这个 1 2 3 就在这里
x left arrow and then this 1 2 3 right here
这整件事被称为发电机
this whole thing is called the generator
它生成数字一到三
it generates the numbers one through three
所以会发生什么
so what happens is
它遍历列表
it iterates through the list
然后它为每个元素运行这个 do 表达式
and then it runs this do expression for each element
所以第一次
so the first time
x 将被设置为值 1
x is going to get set to a value of one
并且 do 将返回三个
and do is going to return three
然后第二次将 x 设置为两个
and then 2nd time x is going to be set to two
这将返回六，依此类推
and this is going to return six and so on
你注意到它返回了一个列表
and you notice that it returns a list
包含该应有表达式的结果
containing the results of that due expression
所以我们在这里给了它一个清单
so we gave it a list here
即使这表示 x 乘以 3
and even though this says x times three
它把结果
it puts the result of that
在列表中
inside of a list
所以在这里比较这两个
so just comparing these two right here
使用理解只是一种更简洁的方式
using a comprehension is just a more succinct way
将一个值列表映射到另一个列表
to map one list of values into another list
我们将使用这样的简单理解
we'll use a simple comprehension like this
对于我们的模板
for our template
但在我们继续之前值得注意
but it's worth noting before we move on
你可以做所有
that you can do all
很酷的东西
sorts of cool stuff with comprehensions
例如假设我们有 t
for example suppose we have t
衬衫尺码和颜色
shirt sizes and colors
我们要生成组合
and we want to generate the combination
我们想要红色和蓝色的小
we want small for red and blue
中等红色和蓝色等等
medium for red and blue and whatnot
为此，我们可以给理解两个生成器
to do that we can give the comprehension two generators
所以这是一个大小的生成器
so here's a generator for the size
然后有一个逗号
then there's a comma
这是颜色的生成器
and here's the generator for the color
然后适当的表达只是把大小和颜色
and then the due expression just puts size and color
元组内部
inside of a tuple
所以如果我们像妮可说的那样运行它，我们会得到小红
so if we run that as nicole said we get small red
小蓝 中红 中蓝 大红 大蓝
small blue medium red medium blue large red large blue
你明白了
and you get the point
像这样使用多个生成器
using multiple generators like this
就像有一个嵌套循环
is like having a nested loop
所以回到我们的模板而不是使用地图
so back in our template instead of using map
我们可以用我们的理解
we can use our comprehension
我们会说四只熊
we'll say four bear
然后列表是
and then the list is
实际上是我们设定的熊名单
actually the list of bears that were set in our
控制器动作
controller action
然后只记得在那里做一个
then just remember to put a do right there
我们可以把这些打印件放在这里
and we can drop this prints right down here
把它存起来
save that away
哦，没有什么要重新编译的
oh there's nothing to recompile
因为我刚刚更改了模板
because I just changed the template
你看我们的名单上有我们的熊
and you see we've got our bears in our list
和之前一样
same as before
这只是感觉很多
this just feels a lot
比我们使用地图的版本更好
nicer than the version we had that used map
现在
now
值得注意的是，您可以在
it's worth noting that you can use comprehensions in
任何电码
any electric code
不仅仅是模板
not just templates
在某些情况下，在特定模板中
in some cases in in particular templates
我认为它们更容易阅读
I think they're easier to read
比使用 e 新功能
than using e new functions
我们还有未使用的展示模板
we still have the show template we haven't used
所以我们需要为它动态生成内容
so we need to dynamically generate content for it
是的
yeah
所以我们需要做的是评估展示模板
so what we need to do is evaluate the show template
在表演动作里面
inside of the show action
所以开始我要复制这个
so to get started I'm going to copy this
我们最终会得到一些重复
we're going to end up with a little bit of duplication
但没关系
but that's okay
模板名称将显示为 ex
the name of the template is going to be show ex
然后就我们的绑定而言
and then in terms of our bindings
我们只是要绑定
we're just going to bind
名称承担价值承担
the name bear to the value bear
这就是我们在这里设置的东西
that's the thing we have set right here
然后对于我们的响应体
then for our response body
我们可以摆脱这个字符串
we can get rid of this string
因为这只是模板内容
because this is just going to be the template content
然后说走，我们会去这个节目模板
then say that away we'll go to this show template
而不是硬编码的名称
and instead of a hard coded name
这里我们将使用小于等于
here we'll use less than % equal
承担这是我们绑定的名称
bear that's the name of the binding we have
然后对于 truan 瀑布
and then for truan falls
我们将拥有
we're going to have
他们的点冬眠
their dot hibernating
把它存起来
save that away
我更改了控制器，所以我需要重新编译
I change the controller so I need to recompile
如果我重新加载处理程序
and if I reload the handler
看看一岁的贝壳熊
check it out shell bears in an age one
泰迪在冬眠吗 是的 他是
is teddy hibernating yes he is
现在
now
我们显然在这里引入了一些重复
we've obviously introduced a bit of duplication here
我们可以清理
which we can clean up
我们如何创建一个名为 render 的新函数
how about we make a new function named render that
然后我们可以在 index 和 show 中重用
we can then reuse in both index and show
是的，然后开始
yeah and to get that started
我只是要复制其中一个实例
I'm just going to copy an instance of one of these
我们将在这里的顶部定义渲染
and we'll define render up at the top here
就这样方便
just so it's handy
我们将其设为私有函数
we'll make it a private function
因为它不会被调用
because it's not going to get called
在这个模块之外
outside of this module
我将粘贴我在下面复制的内容
and I'll paste in what I copied below
好的，现在
all right and now
让我们弄清楚它需要什么参数
let's figure out what arguments it's going to need
好好把握
to take well
它需要 co 和 v
it needs co and v
因为我们将其更新为最后一行
because we update that as the last line
它还需要模板
it also needs the template
我们不想要这个硬涂层在这里
we don't want this hard coated right here
所以我就称它为模板
so I'll just call this the template
我们将把它作为第二个论点
we'll make that the second argument
并且还需要绑定
and also needs the bindings
因为那些
because those
会因动作而异
are going to vary depending on the action
所以让我们把它拿出来，我们就叫它绑定
so let's take this out and we'll just call it bindings
这将是第三个论点
that will be the third argument
我们可以将其默认为一个空列表
and we can default that to an empty list
这就是您将默认参数设置为长生不老药的方式
this is how you set a default parameter an elixir
所以如果我们不提供绑定
so if we don't supply the bindings
它只是一个空列表
it's just going to be an empty list
然后指数下降
then down in index
我们可以继续调用该渲染函数
we can go ahead and call that render function
通过 co 和 v 它会
pass co and v it's going to
成为索引前，我们的绑定是熊将是熊
be index ex and our bindings are bears will be bears
以同样的方式，我将复制它
the same way I'll just copy that
我们可以把它贴在这里展示
and we can paste it down here for show
这里唯一的区别
the only difference here
是不是模板叫show
is the template is called show
它只是一只熊
and it's just a single bear
把它存起来
save that away
重新编译
recompile
现在看起来一切都还很笨拙
and it looks like everything's still hunky dory now
除了想找个借口看理解
besides wanting an excuse to look at comprehensions
你可能想知道为什么
you might be wondering why
我们经历了所有的麻烦来创建一个控制器
we went through all the trouble to create a controller
野生事物模块和这些模板文件
the wild things module and these template files
我们会坚持下去，因为接下来一切都会揭晓
we'll stick around because all will be revealed next